Mobius, Inc. Records MS208
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Audiovisual materials, 1968 -- 2009; MS208.008; 42.0 Linear Feet
  - Audio cassettes and DAT, 1971 -- 2003; MS208.008.005; 1.2 Linear Feet
    - Aud/Mag, 1985 -- 1989; MS208.008.005.103.00164 (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1042. No mention of author. 30 seconds.
    - Aud/Mag, 1985 -- 1989; MS208.008.005.103.00165 (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1043. No mention of author. 60 seconds.
    - MCYN, 1985 -- 1989; MS208.008.005.103.00166 (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1044. No mention of author. 30 seconds.
    - The Nearly Complete Works: Volume One, 1971 -- 1976; MS208.008.005.103.00167; Janzen, Thomas E. (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1206.
    - The Nearly Complete Works: Volume Two, 1976 -- 1979; MS208.008.005.103.00168; Janzen, Thomas E. (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1205.
    - The Nearly Complete Works: Volume Three, 1979 -- 1983; MS208.008.005.103.00169; Janzen, Thomas E. (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1204.
    - The Nearly Complete Works: Volume Four, 1983 -- 1985; MS208.008.005.103.00170; Janzen, Thomas E. (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1203.
    - The Nearly Complete Works: Volume Five, 1984 -- 1987; MS208.008.005.103.00171; Janzen, Thomas E. (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1202. The Last Music, The First Stories.
    - The Nearly Complete Works: Volume Six, 1985 -- 1989; MS208.008.005.103.00172; Janzen, Thomas E. (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1201. Performance Pieces.
    - James Williams Interview, 1995; MS208.008.005.103.00173; Williams, James (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1244. For newsletter?
    - MAG Collaboration Panel Discussion 2, 1996; MS208.008.005.103.00174; Mobius Panel Discussion (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1259. DAT. 2 of 2. See Item 104.
    - Run with Music, 1985 -- 1996; MS208.008.005.103.00175; Raymond, Bob; Lang, Dan (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1295. 60 seconds.
    - Jeanne d'Arc, 1985 -- 1989; MS208.008.005.103.00176 (Box 103)
      Mobius Inventory Number 1227. 12 minutes.
  - Open-reel, 1978 -- 1990; 1978 -- 1986; MS208.008.006; 1.2 Linear Feet
    This subseries contains recordings on open reel audio tape, 1978-1986. Recordings capture the sound of local and international works and experimental music performances.
    Artists represented include Bob Raymond, Dan Lang, Mario Paolli, Jude Aronstein, Victor Young, Julie Rochlin, and Marc Battier.
    - Lot's Wife, 1978 -- 1987; MS208.008.006.104.00001; Paoli, Mario (Box 104)
      Magnetic audio tape
    - Mobius Run, 1978 -- 1990; MS208.008.006.104.00002; Raymond, Bob; Land, Dan (Box 104)
    - Field at Eperimental Music Studio, M.I.T., 1981; MS208.008.006.104.00003; Roads, C (Box 104)
    - Music for 8 Mediation Pieces and Little Mysteries, 1981 -- 1982; MS208.008.006.104.00004 (Box 104)
    - Various manners of looking at the same picture, 1983; MS208.008.006.104.00005; Battier, Marc (Box 104)
    - Mother Peace, 1984-05-16; MS208.008.006.104.00006; Rochlin, Julie (Box 104)
    - Mother Peace, 1984-05-16; MS208.008.006.104.00007; Young, Victor (Box 104)
    - Mother Piece, 1984-05-16; MS208.008.006.104.00008; Aronstein, Jude (Box 104)
    - Lot's Wife, 1986-03-29; MS208.008.006.104.00009 (Box 104)
- Artifacts, 1990 -- 2003; MS208.009; 3.6 Linear Feet
  This series contains a variety of three-dimensional objects, including gifts presented to Mobius, objects used in performances, and promotional items. Included are a number of artifacts used in performances during the 25th anniversary program, "Mobius 25:" boots worn by William Pope L, "A Collection of Images to Consider a Question" used by Donald Burgy, and a suitcase (with jumpsuit) used by Dillon Paul.
  This series is not arranged.
  - Box presented to Mobius Performing Group on the occasion of its 13th anniversary, 1990-02-17; MS208.009.066 (Box 66)
    Box presented to Mobius by Boston-based artist Ronald Wallace, with the following message:
    "This box was presented to the Mobius Performing Group on the occasion of its 13th Anniversary. It contains artifacts and documents relevant to the subject of the Mobius strip and its discoverer, Augustus Ferdinand Mobius. These materials were assembled for the purpose of exploring the relationship between a significant geometrical abstraction which symbolizes the forefront of mathematics and its namesake, an organization of artists whose purpose is to encourage the creation and presentation of art that is challenging and innovative. It is the fervent hope of the undersigned that the contents of this box will be the fertile seeds of further interest and study by members of the Group and its many supporters." - Ronald Wallace, February 17, 1990
  - William Pope L's boots, 2003-05-28; MS208.009.105 (Box 105)
    Boots worn by William Pope L in his Mobius 25 performance, May 28, 2003.
  - Mobius 25 artifacts, 2003-05-28 -- 2003-06-07; MS208.009.106 (Box 106)
    Artifacts related to the 25th anniversary program "Mobius 25" including "A Collection of Images to Consider a Question" used in Donald Burgy's performance, unidentified rolls of toilet paper, and Mobius 25 promotional t-shirts.
  - Dillon Paul's suitcase, 2003-05-28; MS208.009.107 (Box 107)
    Suitcase containing a white jumpsuit and socks used in Dillons Paul's Mobius 25 performance, May 28, 2003.
- Additional accessions, 1983 -- 2015; MS208.010; 3.6 Linear Feet; 13 Digital Object(s)
  This series comprises unprocessed accessions, not yet added to the first nine series. The majority of unprocessed materials are digital photographs and video of performances, 2003-2011. Also included are an interview with Bob Raymond, 1984; electronic copies of printed newsletters, 1983-2002; programs, postcards, and strip calendars, circa 1983-1996; artists' videos, circa 1987-1994; audio recordings of book project interviews, including panel discussions of Mobius history, 1993-1994; WBZ Channel 4 News coverage (video) of Reports from Afield, 2001; and the book This moment: Missives from another world: Thirty years of performances photographed by Bob Raymond, 2015.
  - Mobius digital files, MS208-001
    Contains bags of 50 stabilized zip and floppy disks.
  - Mobius digital files, 1994 -- 2004; MS208-002
    Contains bags of 11 stabilized CD-R disks that includes audio, text, and image files.These digital files document various artist projects created and preformed locally and internationally specifically in Croatia and Macedonia.
  - This moment: Missives from another world: Thirty years of performances photographed by Bob Raymond, 2015; MS208-003; Raymond, Bob; Arsem, Marilyn (Box 1)
  - Bob Raymond interview, 1984-12-28; MS208-004 (Box 2)
    Audio cassette. Mobius inventory #1039
    audiocassette
  - Mobius newsletters, 1983 -- 2002; MS208-005
  - Channeling, 2001-08-22; MS208-006; Arsem, Marilyn; Speare, Jed (Box 3)
    Hi-8 cassette. "Channeling" performed by Marilyn Arsem, Zadar, Croatia. Filmed by Jed Speare. Mobius inventory #311
    videocassette
  - MOBIUS25PIX, 2003 -- 2005; MS208-007
  - MOBIUSPIX_2003, 2003 -- 2004; MS208-008
  - MOBIUSPIX_2004, 2004 -- 2005; MS208-009
  - MOBIUSPIX_2005, 2005 -- 2006; MS208-010
  - MOBIUSPIX_2006, 2006 -- 2007; MS208-011
  - MOBIUSPIX_2007, 2007 -- 2008; MS208-012
  - MOBIUSPIX_2008, MS208-013
  - MOBIUSPIX_2009, 2009 -- 2010; MS208-014
  - MOBIUSPIX_2010, 2010 -- 2011; MS208-015
  - MOBIUSPIX_2011, MS208-016
  - Video, 2004 -- 2009; MS208-017 (Box data_value_missing_629cecc3b25fd7e17b3e59f1022fb38b)
  - Programs, postcards, and strip calendars; "Public Art and the Cultural District: A Planning Report", 1983 -- 1996; MS208-018 (Box 4)
    Programs, postcards, and strip calendars, circa 1983-1996; "Public Art and the Cultural District: A Planning Report" (draft) prepared by the Institute of Contemporary Art for the Boston Redevelopment Authority, December 20, 1987.
    For additional promotional materials, see Series 003.
  - Book project interviews, artists' videos, news coverage of Reports from Afield, 1987 -- 2001; MS208-019 (Box 5)
    Audio recordings of book project interviews, including panel discussions of Mobius history, 1993-1994; artists' videos, circa 1987-1994; WBZ Channel 4 News coverage (video) of Reports from Afield, 2001.
    For additional documentation of the book project, see MS208.003.051.
- Website, 2015-2019; MS208.004741; 1 Web sites
  This series is open for research.
  Webite crawled by DCA to document the presence of Mobius on the web. The website in this series is crawled on an annual basis.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Archived websites can be viewed online using the Internet Archive's Wayback Machine.
  - Mobius, 2015-09-08 -- 2019-10-05; MS208.004742; 1 Web sites